一个陌生男人在我的卧室里
There's a strange man in my bedroom.
不
No.
妈妈 -我在城里
Mum? - I'm in town!
不 回家 赶快回家
No, go home! Go home right now.
宝贝别发这么大火嘛 -妈妈
Darling you're breaking up. - Mum!
好了 我该走了
Right then, I'll be off.
除非…你可以跟我一起走
Unless. . .I don't konw, you could come with me.
总是会像刚才那么危险吗 -是的
Is it always this dangerous? - Yeah.
我离开了多久
How long have I been gone?
大约十二小时
About 12 hours.
好 我不会待很久
Oh. . . ! Right, I won't be long.
我就去看一下我妈妈
I just want to see my mum.
你准备怎么和她说 -我不知道
What you gonna tell her? - I don't konw.
告诉她我去了五十亿年以后
That I've been to the year five billion
但我却只离开了 多久来着
and only been gone, what,
十二小时
12 hours?
不 我只会告诉她我在席琳家过夜了
No, I'll just tell her I spent the night at Shereen's.
一会见
See you later.
你可不许消失
Don't you disappear.
警方寻人启事
我回来了 我昨晚在席琳家
I'm back! I was with Shireen.
她又不高兴了 你在吗
She got all upset again. . . Are you in?
家里怎么样 你都干吗了
So what's been goin' on? How've you been?
怎么了
What?
这是什么表情
What's that face for?
我又不是第一次在外面过夜
It's not the first time I've stayed out all night.
警方寻人启事
请大家帮助
真的是你
It's you.
当然是我啊
Course it's me.
天呐 真的是你 天呐
Oh, my God, it's you. Oh, my God.
洛斯在哪
失踪
你见过洛斯·泰勒吗
你有任何相关消息吗
不是十二个小时 是十二个月
I-it's not 12 hours, it's 12 months.
你离开了整整一年
You've been gone a whole year.
对不起
Sorry!
神秘博士第一季第四集
伦敦的外星人
我在这里煎熬着 日复一日
The hours I sat here -
周复一周 月复一月 独自一人
days and weeks and months - all on my own!
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead,
可你在干什么 "旅行"
and where were you? "Travelling"!
旅行是什么意思
What the hell's it mean, travelling?
这算什么答案
That's no sort of answer!
你问她吧 她不肯告诉我
You ask her, she won't tell me.
她就只会说 "旅行"
That's all she says, "travelling".
我本来就是旅行去了嘛
That's what I was doing.
你的护照还在抽屉里呢
With your passport still in the drawer?
你就扯谎吧你
It's just one lie after another!
我想打电话来着 真的 我只是…
I meant to phone, I really did. I just...
忘了 -忘了一年吗
I forgot. - For a year?
你把我留在家一整年都想不起来打电话
You forgot for a year, and I'm left sitting here? !
我就是不相信你
I just don't believe you!
你就不能告诉我你到底去哪了吗
Why won't you tell me where you've been?
实际上 这是我的错 我可以说是
Actually, it's my fault. I sort of
雇了洛斯做我的旅伴
employed Rose as my companion.
你说的伴侣是指包括性关系的那种吗
When you say companion, is this a sexual relationship?
不是 -不是
No! - No!
那到底怎么回事 就因为你
Then what is it? Because you.
你带着你迷人的微笑大摇大摆走进来
You waltz in here, all charm and smiles,
然后一转眼
and the next thing I know,
她就人间蒸发了
she vanishes off the face of the Earth!
你多老了 四十岁
How old are you then, 40,
还是四十五岁 你是从网上钓到她的吗
45? What, did you find her on the Internet,
在网上假装什么博士
go online and pretend you're a Doctor.
我就是博士 -你能证明吗
I am a Doctor. - Prove it.
尝尝这个
Stitch this, mate.
你到底想过我吗
Did you think about me at all?
我想过 一直都想 只是…
I did, all the time, but...
哪怕一通电话 让我知道你还活着
One phone call. Just to know that you were alive.
对不起 真的对不起
I'm sorry, I really am.
但更让我害怕的是你还不肯说
But d'you know, what terrifies me is that you still can't say.
你到底发生了什么事 洛斯
What happened to you, Rose?
到底是什么事糟到你都不能和我说的地步
What can be so bad that you can't tell me, sweetheart?
你到底去哪了
Where were you?
我不能告诉她 我都不知道从何说起
I can't tell her. I can't even begin.
她永远都不会原谅我的
She's never going to forgive me.
而且我失去了一年的时间
And I missed a year.
这一年好吗 -一般吧
Was it good? - Middling.
你太没用了
You're so useless.
既然惹了这么多麻烦
Well, if it's this much trouble,
你准备留下了吗 -我不知道
are you gonna stay here now? - I don't konw.
反正不能再这样对她了
Can't do that to her again, though.
那我们也不能带上她
Well, she's not coming with us.
确实不可能 -我可不搞全家游
No chance! - I don't do families.
她打了你一耳光
She slapped you!
在时间与空间中旅行了九百年
900 years of time and space
我可从没被谁的妈妈扇过耳光
I've never been slapped by someone's mother.
你那表情
Your face.
很疼的 -你太娘了
It hurt! - You're so gay!
你刚才说九百年
When you say 900 years. . .
那是我的年纪
That's my age.
你九百岁了 -是的
You're 900 years old. - Yeah.
我妈说得对 我们的代沟是有点大
My mum was right. That is one hell of an age gap.
每次和你说话都变得这么疯狂
Every conversation with you just goes mental.
可我又没别人可以倾诉
There's no-one else I can talk to!
我看到的那么多东西
I've seen all that stuff up there,
见识了宇宙之广袤 却一个字都不能说
the size of it, and I can't say a word.
外星人还有太空飞船还有那些…
Aliens and spaceships and things...
而我是地球上唯一一个知道他们存在的人
and I'm the only person on planet Earth who knows they exist.
这不公平
Oh, that's just not fair.
这倒霉催的
Ah, just my luck.
请后退 后退 谢谢
Stay back, please. Back, thank you.
已经封锁了
It's blocked off!
我们离中心还有好远呢
We're miles from the centre.
全城肯定都堵住了
The city must be gridlocked.
整个伦敦恐怕都要关停了
The whole of London must be closing down.
我知道 真不敢相信我正好碰到这个
I know! I can't believe I'm here to see this.
太奇妙了
This is fantastic!
你早就知道这会发生吗 -不
Did you know this was gonna happen? -Nope!
你知道那艘船吗 -不
Do you recognise the ship? - Nope!
你知道它为什么会坠毁吗 -不
Do you know why it crashed? - Nope!
有你在真好 -我觉得也是
So glad I've got you. - I bet you are!
这就是我到处旅行的原因 洛斯
This is why I travel for, Rose.
历史就在我们眼前发生
History happening right in front of us!
那我们去看看啊 不用管交通情况
Well, let's go and see it. Never mind the traffic,
我们有塔迪斯 -最好不要
we've got the TARDIS. - Hmm. Better not.
已经有一艘太空飞船在伦敦中央
With one spaceship in the middle of London,
我可不想再加一艘
I don't wanna shove another on top.
好吧 但是你的看起来像个蓝色大盒子
Yeah. . .but yours looks like a big blue box.
没人会注意到的
No-one's gonna notice.
那可不一定
You'd be surprised.
这样的情况出现时 各色人等都会盯着
Emergency like this, there will be all kinds of people watching.
相信我 塔迪斯需要留在原地
Trust me, the TARDIS stays where it is.
所以历史大事发生 我们却困在这里
So history is happening, and we're stuck here.
对 是的
Yes, we are. . .
又是肯·利文斯通搞的鬼 对不对
This has gotta be Ken Livingstone, isn't...?
我们可以和大家一样
We could do what everyone else does.
去看电视
Watch it on TV.
飞碟坠落伦敦
大本钟被毁
一架飞碟坠落于伦敦中央导致大本钟被毁
Big Ben destroyed as a UFO crash-lands in central London.
飞碟坠落伦敦
警方尽力控制围观者
政府已从全国调集警力增援
Police reinforcements are drafted in from across the country
控制大规模恐慌 劫掠和市民骚动
to control widespread panic, looting and civil disturbance.
并发布了全国紧急通报
A state of national emergency has been declared.
飞碟坠落伦敦
汤姆·海金森从现场发回报道
Tom Hitchinson is at the scene.
警方呼吁公众不要惊慌
The police urge the public not to panic.
外星人应急响应及求助热线
如果你担心家人或朋友
Here's the helpline number on screen right now
请拨打屏幕下方的求助热线
if you're worried about friends or family.
军方正在监控是否有更多太空飞船的出现
The military are on the lookout for more spaceships.
得到进一步确认之前 北美所有机场的
Until then all flights in North American airspace
飞机均已禁飞
have been grounded.
飞碟坠落伦敦
军方潜水员在泰晤士河中寻找尸体
军方向飞碟坠毁现场派出了潜水员
The army are sending divers into the wreck of the space ship,
没人知道他们会发现什么
no-one knows what they're going to find.
总统将在白宫向全国发表电视直播讲话
The President will address the nation live from the White House,
但联合国秘书长已经呼吁大家
but the Secretary General has asked
时刻注意天空出现的异常情况
that people watch the skies.
我别无选择 -你伤了你妈妈的心
I've got no choice! - You broke your mother's heart.
欢迎他或者落得个再也见不到你的结果
Make him welcome or risk never seeing you again.
还得我像哄孩子一样哄她
And I cradled her like a child...
我在听新闻呢
Oi! I'm trying to listen!
飞碟坠落伦敦 首相府尚未发表评论
刚刚得到消息…
News just coming in...
让我们把镜头转给正在河边的汤姆
and we go to Tom at the embankment.
飞碟坠落伦敦
军方潜水员在泰晤士河中找到尸体
他们找到了一具尸体
They've found a body.
目前还尚未证实
It's unconfirmed
但据传在失事地点找到了一具尸体
but I'm being told a body's been found in the wreckage,
一具非地球生物的尸体
a body of non-terrestrial origins.
它已经被带上岸了
It's being brought ashore.
太空飞船的废墟中疑似发现了一具尸体
A body of some sort has been found inside the wreckage of a spacecraft.
猜猜谁约我出去了 比利·克鲁特
Guess who asked me out? Billy Croot!
未经证实的报道称
Unconfirmed reports say
飞碟坠落伦敦
军方潜水员在泰晤士河中找到尸体
该尸体确实来自外星
the body IS of extra-terrestrial origin.
伦敦中心正在发生一起重大事件
An extraordinary event unfolding here live in central London.
尸体已被转移到一处重兵把守的停尸房
The body is being transferred to a secure-unit mortuary,
具体位置目前尚不清楚 道路…
whereabouts as yet unknown. Roads in...
飞碟坠落伦敦 武装警察在伦敦街头巡逻
你贴机翼的时候
And when you've stuck your fins on
可以用奶油把它整个盖住
you can cover the whole lot in butter-cream.
瞧啊 用你喜欢的颜色上好糖霜
Ooh look at that! Then, ice it any colour you want.
这是我刚刚做好的一个
And here's one I made a little bit earlier...
看啊 你的独家太空飞船 美味可口
And look at that, your very own spaceship, ready to eat.
再加一点点特别的口味
And for something a little extra special...
飞碟坠落伦敦
太空飞船中的尸体被送入医院看管
阿尔比恩医院
Albion Hospital.
我们还不知道它是死是活
We still don't know if it's alive or dead.
白厅否认一切
Whitehall's denying everything.
但尸体已经被带到了阿尔比恩医院
But the body has been brought here, Albion Hospital.
由于道路拥堵 这是离河最近的医院
With roads closed, it's the closest to the river.
我得知现在艾斯奎斯将军正在进入医院
I'm being told that's General Asquith now entering the hospital.
大楼里的人已被疏散
The building has been evacuated,
其他病人也已经转移到了街上
patients moved out onto the streets.
警方仍未确认在这大楼里
The police still won't confirm the presence of an alien body
有外星人的尸体
contained inside those walls.
让我看看
Let's have a look, then.
老天爷啊
Good God!
这是真的吗
And that's real?
这不是骗局或假人什么的吗
It's not a hoax or a dummy, or... ?
我对颅骨进行了X光扫描
I've X-rayed the skull.
里面的结构我从未见过
It's wired up inside like nothing I've ever seen before.
没人能造假到这种水平
No one could make this up.
大批专家正在赶来
We've got experts being flown in.
在他们来之前 把这东西藏好
Until they arrive, get that out of sight.
抱歉 长官
Excuse me, sir.
我知道现在是紧急状态
I know it's a state of emergency
而且流言满天飞 但是
and there's a lot of rumour flying around, but
他们说的是真的吗 关于首相的事情
is it true what they're saying? About the Prime Minister?
首相的去向依然迷雾重重
Mystery still surrounds the whereabouts of the Prime Minister.
自从紧急状态开始后就没人见过他了
He's not been seen since the emergency began.
反对党正在大肆批评他缺乏领导能力及…
The opposition are criticising his lack of leadership and...
等等
Hold on.
那是约瑟夫·格林 哈特利戴尔的国会议员
Oh, that's Joseph Green, MP for Hartleydale.
他是国会下院
He's Chairman of the Parliamentary Commission
监控出口甜食含糖标准委员会主席
on the Monitoring of Sugar Standards in Exported Confectionery.
恕我直言 眼下最要紧的人物可不是他
With respect, hardly the most important person right now.
英德拉·加奈什 先生 国防部初级秘书
Indra Ganesh, sir, Junior Secretary with the MOD.
我将是您的联系人 -他到底在哪
I'll be your liaison. - Where the hell is he?
我们能单独谈谈吗 先生
If we could talk in private, sir?
请跟我上楼
Follow me upstairs.
抱歉
Excuse me. . .
哈丽特·琼斯 弗莱德尔北区议员
Harriet Jones, MP for Flydale North.
不好意思 不能等等吗
I'm sorry, can't it wait?
但我的确预约了三点一刻和首相见面
But I did have an appointment at 3:15.
对 可一架飞船刚在伦敦中心坠毁
Yes. Then a spaceship crashed in the middle of London.
我想您的安排可能得拖一拖了
I think the schedule might have changed.
您听说那外星人尸体的事了吗 先生
You've heard about the alien body, sir?
别说那个了
Never mind that.
他在哪里 首相在哪里
Where is he? Where's the Prime Minister?
没人知道 他人间蒸发了
No one knows, he's disappeared.
我得通知您
I have to inform you,
由于全城一片混乱
with the city gridlocked
全体内阁成员又都被堵在伦敦城外
and the Cabinet stranded outside London,
所以现在您成了代理首相
that makes you become Acting Prime Minister.
马上就任
With the immediate effect.
天呐 等等
Oh, Lord! Oh, hold on.
抱歉 我的胃有点紧张 那好吧
Pardon me. I-it's a nervous stomach. Anyway.
玛格丽特·布莱恩 军情五处的
Margaret Blaine, she's with MI5.
没有更多信息了 先生
There's no more information, sir.
我亲自护送首相从内阁会议室上了专车
I personally escorted the PM from the Cabinet Room to his car.
这位是奥利弗·查尔斯 交通联络官
This is Oliver Charles, Transport Liaison.
车消失了 没有任何记录 先生
The car's disappeared. There's no record of it, sir.
真的是人间蒸发了 -我们先进去
Literally vanished. - Right. Inside,
告诉我一切
tell me everything.
先生 这是应急条例
Er, sir...emergency protocols,
详述外星人入侵时
detailing actions to be taken
英国政府应该采取的
by the Government of the Great Britain
相应行动
in the event of an alien incursion.
对 很好
Right, good!
妈呀
Blimey!
抱歉
Pardon me.
该工作了
Get to work, eh?
你要去哪里
And where'd you think you're going?
哪里都不去
Nowhere.
对我来说那里面人气太旺了
It's...just a bit human in there for me.
历史性的事件刚刚发生
History just happened.
而他们在讨论哪里买得到半价的假充值卡
They're talking about where you can buy dodgy top-up cards half-price.
我只是出来走走而已 没别的
I'm only off on a wander, that's all.
对 泰晤士河上漂着一架飞船
Right. A spaceship on the Thames,
而你只是在闲逛
and you're just wandering.
这和我根本无关 反正不是外星人入侵
Nothing to do with me! It's not an invasion.
这真的只是着陆时坠毁了
That was a genuine crash-landing.
下降角度 烟雾颜色 所有迹象都是
Angle of descent, colour of smoke, everything.
毫无作假痕迹
It was perfect.
所以呢
So?
所以也许这就是第一类接触呢
So maybe this is it, first contact.
是人类与外星人间
The day mankind officially
首次正式联系上的一天
comes into contact with an alien race.
我才不会插手
I'm not interfering.
因为你们得自己处理这件事
Cos you've got to handle this on your own.
只有这样 人类文明才算真正成熟了
That's when the human race finally grows up!
在今天早上
Just this morning,
你们还是渺小脆弱的生物呢
you were all tiny and small and made of clay!
现在你们踏出第一步了
Now you can expand!
你们不需要我 去欢庆历史性的一天吧
You don't need me. Go and celebrate history.
和你妈妈共度美好时光吧
Spend time with your mom.
你要保证你不会丢下我走掉
Promise you won't disappear.
这么着吧
Tell you what.
塔迪斯的钥匙
TARDIS key.
是时候给你一把了
About time you have one.
再见
See you later.
外星人着陆了
帅哥 快回来一起开派对啊
Oi, gorgeous, come back and join the party!
欢迎来到我们的世界
你好 外星人
天呐
Oh, my God!
博士
Oi! Doctor!
Doctor!
还没人给你捎杯咖啡吧
I bet no one's brought you a coffee.
谢谢 -不客气
Thank you. - Pleasure.
你还是不能进
You still can't go in.
可恶 我的妙计被你看穿了
Damn, you've seen through my cunning plan.
我很抱歉 但这不可能
Look, I'm sorry, it's just impossible.
两分钟都不行吗
Not even for two minutes?
我来这里的机会并不多
I don't get many chances to walk these corridors,
我不是"宝贝" 只是个忠诚的后座议员
I'm hardly one of the "Babes", just a faithful backbencher.
指"布莱尔宝贝" 即1997年工党大选获胜的一百余位女议员
我知道现在新世界的大门
And I know we've had a brave new world
正在向我们敞开 这实在是太棒了
land right on our doorstep, and that's wonderful.
我想 这可能很棒吧
I think that's...probably wonderful.
不过 平淡无奇的生活还要继续
Nevertheless, ordinary life keeps ticking away.
我需要递交这文件
I need to enter this paper.
格林先生 我知道您很忙
Oh, Mr Green, sir, I know you're busy,
但您能否将这个纳入下次内阁会议的议程中
but could you put this on the next Cabinet agenda?
这是什么 -关于乡村医院的
What is it? - Cottage hospitals.
我研究出了一种系统
I've worked out a system
这样乡村医院就不必与
where cottage hospitals need not be excluded
高等医院分离开来
from Centres of Excellence.
我母亲正住在弗莱德尔养老院
You see, my mother's in the Flydale Infirmary,
那是我的选区
that's my constituency,
是个小地方 你可能不知道
tiny little place, you wouldn't know it
但这让我有机会 -看在老天的份上
but it gives me a chance to... - By all the saints,
看清楚点好吗 大姐
get some perspective, woman!
我忙着呢
I'm busy!
紧急条例 绝密
启用Δ防御计划 快
Defence Plan Delta! Come on!
出动 出动
Move! Move!
它是活的
It's alive.
分头行动
Spread out,
通知外面 立即全面封锁
tell the perimeter it's a lockdown.
天呐它还活着
Oh, my God it's still alive!
快去
Do it!
米克 特里 马上去侧间
Mick! Terry! Side rooms! Now!
安全
Clear!
All clear!
继续搜索 -安全
Keep it moving! - Clear!
我发誓 它原来是死的
I swear, it was dead...
昏迷 休克 休眠 都有可能
Coma, shock, hibernation, anything...
它是什么样的
What does it look like?
它还在这里
It's still here.
你好啊
Hello.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
你为什么要开枪
What did you do that for?
它被吓着了
It was scared!
它很害怕
白宫直接把电话打到我这里
I have the White House phoning me direct
因为唐宁街不接电话
because Downing Street won't answer their calls!
这真是太离谱了
This is outrageous!
我们都还没开始进行疫苗项目呢
We haven't even started the vaccination programme.
真是让人震惊
This is appalling!
所有国家都在关注英国
The nations of the world are watching the United Kingdom.
这只是一点小乱子而已
Well, it has all been a bit of a shock.
这是现代历史上最大的危机
It's the greatest crisis in modern history,
而您什么都没做
and you've done nothing.
您的行为真是可耻 先生
Your behaviour has been shameful, sir!
在此坐镇的本该是您
You're supposed to be in charge.
我们需要积极正确的领导
We need positive leadership.
整个首都都瘫痪了
The capital's ground to a halt.
而且我们只能假设
Furthermore, we can only assume
首相的失踪
the Prime Minister's disappearance
是因外星人的某些敌对行为而造成的
is the direct result of hostile alien action,
而您做了什么呢 什么都没做 -抱歉
and what've you been doing? Nothing! - Sorry.
抱歉 我想我现在就是首相
Sorry, I thought I was Prime Minister now.
只是在相位空缺的情况下
Only by default!
这可不太好
Oh-h-h, that's not fair,
我可正乐在其中呢
I've been having such fun.
你觉着这好玩吗
You think this is fun?
这工作太逗了
It's a hoot, this job.
说实话 太欢乐了
Honestly, it's super!
抱歉啊
Oh, excuse me.
这到底怎么回事
What's going on here?
其他内阁成员在哪里
Where's the rest of the Cabinet?
他们为什么没坐飞机过来
Why haven't they been airlifted in?
我取消了行程 反正他们只会碍手碍脚
I cancelled it. They'd get in the way.
我又来了
Oops, there I go.
还有我
And me!
我在扭屁屁呢
I'm...shaking my booty.
先生 根据紧急条例第五章
Sir! Under Section 5 of the Emergency Protocols,
我有权解除你的指挥权
it is my duty to relieve you of command.
如果必要 我甚至可以对全国实施军事管制
And by God, I'll put this country under martial law if I have to.
我好害怕呀
Ooh I'm scared
我是说
I mean. . .
简直吓死我了
that's hair-raising.
就是这个意思
I mean, literally.
看着
Look.
我以为外星人就长那个样子
I just assumed that's what aliens looked like.
你却说它就是一只普通的地球猪
You're saying it's an ordinary pig, from Earth?
就像美人鱼一样
More like a mermaid.
维多利亚时期的马戏团经常把猫的骷髅
Victorian showmen used to draw the crowds by
和鱼尾粘在一起 称其为美人鱼
taking the skull of a cat gluing into a fish,
以此来吸引观众的眼球
then calling it a mermaid.
现在有人拿一只猪
Now someone's taken a pig,
改造了它的大脑 再重新粘合起来
opened up its brain, stuck bits on.
之后把它绑在那艘飞船里 使其坠毁
Then they strapped it in that ship, made it dive-bomb,
它一定吓坏了
it must've been terrified.
他们拿这动物开了一个天大的玩笑
They've taken this animal and turned it into a joke.
所以这是假的 是仿造的 像美人鱼一样
So it's a fake, a pretend, like the mermaid.
但他们用来扩容它大脑的技术
But the technology augmenting its brain,
却是地球上前所未见的
it's like nothing on Earth.
是外星技术 外星人假造外星人
It's alien. Aliens are faking aliens?
他们为什么要这么做
Why would they do that?
博士
Doctor?
这杯敬那些火星人 -敬火星人
Here's to the Martians! - The Martians!
我正打算找你呢
I was gonna come and see ya.
某些人还没跟米奇道歉呢
Someone owes Mickey an apology.
对不起 -不是说你
I'm sorry. - Not you.
又不能怨我
Well, it's not my fault.
凭心而论 我还能怎么想
Be fair, what was I supposed to think?
你不见了 人们还会怀疑谁
You disappear, who do they turn to?
当然是你男朋友
Your boyfriend.
我被传讯了整整五次 五次啊
Five times I was taken in for questioning. Five times!
没有证据 怎么可能有 不是吗
No evidence. Of course, there couldn't be, could there?
还有她 你妈妈
And her, your mother.
在邻居之间四处传播流言 对我指指点点
Whispering round the estate, pointing the finger.
还在我邮箱里塞那些乱七八糟的东西
Stuff through my letterbox
这些都是因为你
all cos of you.
我没想到我会离开这么久
I didn't think I'd be gone so long.
我一直在等你 洛斯
And I waited for you, Rose!
整整12个月 我都在等你和博士回来
12 months, waiting for you and the Doctor to come back.
慢着 你认识那个博士
Hold on. You knew about the Doctor?
那你怎么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
是啊 为什么不说 洛斯
Yeah, why not, Rose?
你要我怎么告诉她你去哪儿了
How could I tell her where you went?
现在告诉我
Tell me now!
我是打算说 因为你现在哪也去不了了
I might as well, cos you're stuck here.
博士已经走了
The doctor's gone.
就在刚才 那个盒子消失不见了
Just now, that box thing just faded away.
你在说什么 -他不要你了
What d'you mean? - He's left you.
他就是这种男朋友
Some boyfriend he turned out to be.
他不会就这么走了的 他答应过我
He wouldn't just go. He promised me.
他把你甩了 洛斯
Aw, he's dumped you, Rose,
一个人回到太空去了 你现在是什么感觉
sailed off into space. How does it feel?
现在你和我们这些地球人一样
Now you are left behind
被扔在这里了
with the rest of us Earthlings.
慢慢习惯吧
Get used to it!
按说他会跟我说一声的
But he would've said.
你们两个究竟在说什么 到底怎么回事
What are you two chimps going on about? What's going on?
这个博士究竟怎么了
What's this Doctor done now?
呵呵 他跑了
Huh! He's vamoosed!
他没有 他把这个留给了我
He's not! Cos he gave me this.
他不是我男朋友 米奇 他没那么简单
He's not my boyfriend, Mickey, he's better than that.
他比这重要的多 他…
He's much more important. And he. . .
我就说嘛
I said so!
妈妈 妈妈 你先回去
Mum! Mum! Go inside!
别站在这儿 你先回去 妈妈
Don't stand there! Go inside, Mum!
这究竟是怎么做到的
How'd you do that, then?
好吧 我骗了你 我去看了一眼
OK, so I lied. I went for a look.
整个坠毁事件都是个阴谋
The whole crash-landing's a fake.
我想也是 简直太巧了
I thought so - just too perfect.
竟然撞大本钟 得了吧 所以我就想
I mean, hitting Big Ben, come on! So I thought,
咱们去看看那个飞行员 -我妈妈来了
"let's go and have a look at the pilot." - My mum's here.
真是如我所愿
Oh, just what I need.
你休想把这里变成你家
Don't you dare make this place domestic!
你毁了我的生活 博士
You ruined my life, Doctor.
大家都以为她死了
They thought she was dead.
因为你 我成了杀人嫌疑犯
I was a murder suspect because of you.
我说什么来着 当自己家了
You see what I mean? Domestic!
我敢打赌 你甚至都不记得我的名字
I bet you don't even remember my name!
里奇
Ricky.
是米奇 -不 是里奇
It's Mickey. - No, it's Ricky.
我以为我知道自己叫什么
I think I know my own name!
你才"以为"你知道自己的名字
You think you know your own name?
你是有多蠢啊
How stupid are you?
妈妈 不要 哪儿也别去
Mum, don't! Don't go anywhere.
也别打起来
Don't start a fight.
妈妈 不是这样的 他不是…
Mum! It's not like that, he's not. . .
我马上就回去 等我一分钟
I'll be up in a minute hold on!
那真的是一艘太空飞船吗 -是的
That was a real spaceship? - Yep.
这么说全是谎话了
So it's all a pack of lies.
然后呢 它们是要入侵吗
What is it then? Are they invading?
多有趣的入侵方法 把全世界的人都惊到了
Funny way to invade, putting the world on red alert.
想法很好啊 它们究竟想干什么
Good point. So what they up to?
危机还在继续
As the crisis continues,
政府部门表现得缺乏领导力
the Government shows remarkable lack of leadership,
整个国家充斥着各种流言
paranoia sweeps the country.
当局已经将三起公共袭击事件
There've been at least three reports of public assaults
定性为疑似外星人所为
on people possibly identified as aliens.
现在我们把时间交给汤姆·海金森
Now back to Tom Hitchinson.
还会有更多飞船来地球吗
Are there more ships to come?
它们有什么目的
And what's their intention?
当局希望 如果有谁了解任何相关信息
The authorities are now asking, if anyone knows anything,
或发现过任何可疑迹象 请拨打该号码
if any previous sighting has been made, then call this number.
外星人紧急热线
我们需要您的帮助
We need your help.
外星人紧急热线
是的 我看到了一个真正的外星人
Yes, I've seen one, I really have, an alien.
她和他在一起
And she's with him.
我女儿和他在一起 我女儿处境危险
My daughter, she's with him and she's not safe.
天呐 她现在处境很危险
Oh, my God, she's not safe.
我见到了一个外星人 我还知道他的名字
I've seen an alien and I know his name.
他叫博士
He's called the Doctor.
博士
是一个盒子 一个蓝色的盒子
It's a box, a blue box.
蓝盒子
我女儿叫它塔迪斯
She called it a TARDIS.
塔迪斯
红色警戒
博士
你在下面干什么
So what you doing down there?
里奇 -米奇
Ricky... - Mickey.
里奇 如果我告诉你
Ricky, if I was to tell you what I was doing
我怎么修理我酷炫的时间飞船控制系统
to the controls of my frankly magnificent timeship,
你能听懂哪怕一丁点吗
would you even begin to understand?
应该听不懂… -那就闭嘴
I suppose not. . .- Shut it, then.
你交的这叫什么朋友 -他是想惹你发火
Some friend you've got. - He's winding you up.
我真的很抱歉
I am sorry.
好吧 -真的对不起
OK. - I am, though.
我每天都在找你
Every day, I looked.
我走遍了大街小巷
On every street corner, wherever I went.
找那个蓝盒子 找了整整一年
Looking for a blue box. For a whole year.
对我来说只过了几天而已
It's only been a few days for me.
我说不准 在盒子里很难分清时间
I dunno, it's hard to tell inside this thing
可我发誓 我只离开了你短短几天而已
but I swear, it's just a few days since I left you.
所以你还没来得及想我
Not enough time to miss me, then.
我想你了
I did miss you.
我也想你
I missed you.
那么在这12个月里
So, um, in 12 months. . .
你去和别人约会了吗
have you been seeing anyone else?
没有
Nope.
好 -主要是大家都以为我杀了你
OK... - Mainly cos everyone thinks I murdered you.
好吧
Right.
既然你回来了
So, now that you've come back. . .
你会留下来吗
are you gonna stay?
搞定了
Got it!
雷达修好了 可以往前回看12个小时
Patched in the radar, looped it back 12 hours
这样就可以跟踪那艘飞船的飞行轨迹了
so it followed the flight of that spaceship.
看这儿 等一下
Here we go, hold on.
别这样
Come on!
这是那艘飞船飞向地球的轨迹 看到了吗
That's the spaceship on its way to Earth, see?
除了… 等一下
Except! Hold on. . .
看见了吗 那艘飞船在着陆前
See? The space-ship did a slingshot
绕着地球飞行了一圈
round the Earth before it landed.
什么意思
What's that mean?
这个飞船本身就是从地球上发射的
It came from Earth in the first place.
发射升空 再落回地面
Went up and came back down.
不管那些外星生物究竟是什么
Whoever those aliens are,
它们可不是刚来到地球
They haven't just arrived.
它们已经在地球上待了一阵子了
They've been here a while.
问题是 它们都做了什么
Question is, what've they been doing?
效果如何 穿在身上紧不紧
What d'you think, how's the compression?
我觉得腰部有点绷得慌了
I think I've got too much ballast round the middle.
舒服多了
That's better!
我们必须先修理好气体交换系统
We must fix the gas exchange.
这样太可笑了
It's getting ridiculous.
我倒觉得这样更像人类了
I don't know, seems human to me. . .
最好处理掉他的人皮
Better get rid of his skin.
真讨厌 我还挺喜欢当奥利弗的
Shame, I quite enjoyed being Oliver.
他有一个老婆 一个情人
He had a wife, a mistress
还和一个年轻的农民有一腿
and a young farmer.
天呐 我都要忙死了
God, I was busy!
开工了
Back to work.
我现在可以号令军队了
I have an army to command!
小心点 我们还没到这一步呢
Careful now. We're not there yet.
阿斯奎斯将军 我们收到了高优先级的预警
General Asquith. Sir, we've had a priority alarm,
是九号代码 确认是九号代码
it's Code Nine, confirmed Code Nine.
好 很好 九号代码
Right. Good. Code Nine.
那是什么来着
Which would mean...?
紧急条例一旦生效
In the event of emergency protocols being activated,
我们的软件会自动开始
our software automatically searches
在所有通信渠道搜索关键词
all communications for keywords.
其中一个关键词是 博士
And one of those words is "Doctor".
我想我们找到他了 长官
I think we've found him, sir.
什么博士
What sort of Doctor?
他是什么人
Who is he?
显然他是某种处理外星事务的专家
Evidently, he's some sort of expert in extraterrestrial affairs
终极专家
the ultimate expert!
我们需要他 长官
We need him, sir,
我们现在就需要他
we need him here right now.
你这有几个频道
How many channels you get?
基本收费频道都有
All the basic packages.
你还能看体育频道
You get Sports channels?
有 能看足球
Yes, I get the football.
等一下 我认识这些人
Hold on. I know that lot.
看起来政府正在召集外星专家前来会商
But likely that the government's bringing in alien-specialists,
他们花费毕生心血
'those people who've devoted their lives
研究外太空的一切
to studying outer space.'
UNIT 联合国特别情报小组
UNIT, United Nations Intelligence Taskforce.
都是好人
Good people.
你怎么认识他们的
How d'you know 'em?
因为他为他们工作
Cos he's worked for them.
别以为我12个月来光闲着了 博士
Oh, yeah, don't think I sat on my backside for 12 months, Doctor,
我研究了你的背景
I read up on you.
在网上和历史书里仔细找
Look deep enough on the Internet or in history books
都能找到他的名字 所到之处死一堆人
there's his name. Followed by a list of the dead.
很好 好样的 里奇
That's nice, good boy, Ricky
如果你认识他们 为什么不去帮忙
If you know 'em, why not go and help?
他们认不出我了
They wouldn't recognise me.
我变得跟以前不一样了
I've changed a lot since the old days.
而且 现在世界正经历剧变
Besides, the world's on a knife-edge.
外面有外星人 还有假外星人
There's aliens out there - and fake aliens.
我这个外星人还是不要去搅和了
I wanna keep this alien out of the mix.
我要伪装起来
I'm going undercover.
最好把塔迪斯藏起来
I'd better keep the Tardis out of sight.
里奇 你有车
Ricky, you've got a car,
你来开车 -去哪儿
you can do some driving. - Where to?
交通恢复了
The roads are clearing.
咱们去看看那艘飞船
Let's gonna have a look at that spaceship.
不许动
Do not move!
洛斯
Rose!
把手举过头顶 你们被捕了
Raise your hands above your heads! You are under arrest!
带我去见你们的上司
Take me to your leader.
我的女儿
My daughter...
这车有点高级啊
This is a bit posh!
如果知道被捕是这种感觉
If I'd known it would be like this,
好几年前我就要试试了
being arrested, I would've done it years ago.
我们不是被捕 这是在护送我们
We're not being arrested, we're being escorted.
去哪儿 -你觉得呢
Where to? - Where d'you think?
唐宁街
Downing Street.
开玩笑 -我没有
You're kidding! - I'm not!
唐宁街十号 -就是那里
10 Downing Street? - That's the one!
我的天呐
Oh, my God!
我要去唐宁街十号了
I'm going to 10 Downing Street?
为什么 -我不想这么说但是米奇是对的
How come? - I hate to say it, but Mickey was right.
这么多年我拜访这颗星球太多次
Over the years I've visited this planet, a lot of times,
我已经被…注意到了
and I've been. . .noticed.
现在他们需要你
Now they need you.
就像新闻里说的
Like it said on the news,
他们在召集具有外星知识的专家
they're gathering experts in alien knowledge.
那些人里谁是最权威的呢
Who's the biggest expert of the lot?
帕特里克·摩尔爵士 1923-2012 著名业余天文学家
帕特里克·摩尔 -除了他
Patrick Moore. - Apart from him.
你就是喜欢这种感觉
Don't you just love it.
劳合·乔治 1863-1945 曾任英国首相
跟你说 我以前跟劳合·乔治斗酒
Ah, I'm telling you! Lloyd George,
完全喝不过他
he used to drink me under the table.
现在谁是首相
Who's the Prime Minister now?
我怎么知道 我一年没在这儿
How should I know? I missed a year.
我的天呐
Oh, my God!
所以她没事吗
So she's OK, then?
她没有惹什么麻烦吧
She's not in any trouble?
我能说的就是
All I can say is that
国家可能需要您女儿和她同伴
your daughter and her companion might be in a position
提供力所能及的帮助
to help the country.
我们需要知道她是怎么跟那个人联系的
We'll need to know how she made contact with this man.
如果他是人类的话
If he is a man.
好了 你们可以走了
Right, off you go, then.
我需要单独和泰勒夫人谈谈 谢谢
I need to talk with Mrs Tyler on my own, thank you.
哈丽特·琼斯 弗莱德尔北区议员
Harriet Jones, MP Flydale North.
女士们先生们 请集中过来
Ladies and gentlemen, can we convene?
请尽快
Quick as we can please.
这边 右手边
This way, on the right.
提醒你们一下 请不要摘下身份卡
Can I remind you ID cards are to be worn at all times.
这是您的身份卡
Here's your ID card.
抱歉 您的同伴无权进入
I'm sorry, your companion doesn't have clearance.
没有她我哪儿也不去
I don't go anywhere without her.
九号代码是您 不是她
You're the Code Nine, not her.
抱歉 博士
Now, I'm sorry, er...Doctor,
是该叫您博士吧
It's the Doctor, isn't it?
她需要留在外面
She'll have to stay outside.
她得跟我在一起
She's staying with me.
您看 连我都不能进去
Look, even I don't have clearance to go in there.
我不能让她进去 没得商量
I can't let her in. That's a fact.
没关系 你去吧
That's ok...You go.
不好意思 您是博士吗
Excuse me, are you the Doctor?
你确定吗 -现在不行 我们很忙
Are you sure? - Not now! We're busy,
你就不能回家吗
can't you go home?
我只需要单独和他谈谈
I just need a word in private.
您无权入内 不要纠缠了
You haven't clearance. Leave it!
我叫保安来送您出去
I'll leave you with security.
不用了 我来照看她 让我派点用处
It's all right, I'll look after her. Let me be of some use.
跟我走走吧
Walk with me.
不要停
Just keep walking. . .
就这样 不要四处看
That's right, don't look round.
哈丽特·琼斯 弗莱德尔北区议员
Harriet Jones MP, Flydale North.
你的这位朋友
This friend of yours,
他确实是一位专家 对吗
he's an expert, is that right?
他了解 了解外星人的事吗
He know... H-he knows about aliens?
您找他有什么事吗
Why'd you wanna to know?
女士们先生们 请安静
Ladies and gentlemen, may I have your attention, please?
正如各位手中的摘要中所写
As you see from the summary in front of you,
这艘飞船的飞行员是一只类猪生物
the ship had one porcine pilot.
当然最有趣的部分发生在三天前
Of course the really interesting bit happened three days ago,
看到了吗 归档在"其他"一栏
See? Filed away under "Any other business".
北海 一颗卫星探测到了一个信号
The North Sea. A satellite detected a signal,
在水面下180米深的地方发出的辐射信号
a little blip of radiation at 100 fathoms.
似乎那里有什么东西
Like there's something's down there.
你们正准备调查
You were just about to investigate,
结果发生了这件事
next thing you know, this happens.
太空飞船 猪 转移大众注意力
Spaceships, pigs, massive diversion
为什么
from what?
他们把人变成了张皮
They turn the body into a suit,
里面的东西用人皮作伪装
a disguise, for the thing inside!
没事 我相信你
It's all right, I believe you.
那是外星人
It's... it's, alien.
这里面肯定有什么高科技
But they must have some serious technology behind this.
如果我们可以找出来 就可以加以利用
If we could find it, we could use it.
天呐 这不是..
Oh, my God. Is that...?
哈丽特 天呐
Harriet, for God's sake!
这可不是开玩笑 你不能到处晃悠
This is beyond a joke, you cannot just wander...
天呐 这是首相大人
Oh, my God. That's the Prime Minister.
如果是外星人假造了这起坠毁
If aliens fake an alien crash
和外星人驾驶员 他们能有什么好处
and an alien pilot, what do they get?
我们
Us.
他们就能得到我们了
They get us.
这不是为了转移注意力 这是陷阱
It's not a diversion, it's a trap.
有人调皮捣蛋了吗
Has someone been naughty?
里面比外面大
It was bigger on the inside.
我不知道 我又不懂太空飞船
I don't know! What do I know about spaceships?
这就是让我担心的
That's what worries me. You see,
这个男人是个麻烦
this man is classified as trouble,
也就意味着 跟他牵扯上的人
which means that anyone associated with him...
也是麻烦
is trouble.
而我的工作就是
And that's my job,
解决麻烦
eliminating trouble.
这不可能
But that's not possible.
他今天下午离开了
He left this afternoon.
我是说 首相离开了唐宁街
I mean, the Prime Minister left Downing Street,
他被开车送走了
he was driven away.
谁告诉你的
And who told you that?
是我
Me.
这是冲我们来的
This is about us!
外星专家 唯一知道如何与他们战斗的人
Alien experts, the only people who know how to fight them
被聚集在一处
gathered together in one room.
不好意思 我拯救世界的时候您能别放屁吗
Excuse me. D'you mind not farting while I'm saving the world?
你更喜欢不出声但却致命的那种吗
Would you rather silent but deadly?
我们是斯利辛
We are the Slitheen.
多谢你们始终佩戴着身份证明
Thank you all for wearing your ID. Cards.
可以帮助我们辨识尸体
They'll help to identify the bodies.
下集预告
昨天我们刚看到了新世界的黎明
Yesterday saw the start of a brave new world.
今天也许我们将目睹新世界的终结
Today might see it end.
如果你想要外星人
Oi. If you want aliens, you've got 'em.
他们就在唐宁街里
They're inside Downing Street.
地球正式开战
Planet Earth is at war.
所有人快跑
Everybody run!
斯利辛到底是谁 -外星人
Who exactly are Slitheen? - They're aliens.
我能拯救世界却要失去你
I could save the world but lose you.